Finding Aid for Lurie Terrace records, 1961-2008
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Lurie Terrace records 1961-2008
Lurie Terrace.
2009099 Bb 2
Ann Arbor, Michigan, apartment building for senior citizens of modest means; records of Senior Citizens Housing of Ann Arbor, the organization administering Lurie Terrace, including board minutes, office files, newsletters, and photograph albums and scrapbooks.
10 linear feet
5 oversize volumes
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The records came from Lurie Terrace (donor no. 10122 ) in 2008-09.
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The record group is open to research.
Lurie Terrace, an apartment building for senior citizens with modest means, was dedicated in October 1964. Located on West Huron Street in Ann Arbor, Michigan, the building stands eight stories tall and is comprised of 142 units. The idea for the building was spearheaded by Shata Ling who in 1956 had founded the Senior Citizens Guild. Concerned about the need for affordable housing for seniors, Shata Ling, when learning of a government loan program for building senior housing, helped to establish in 1961 Senior Citizens Housing of Ann Arbor Inc. This organization would locate appropriate property, obtain the services of an architectural firm, and secure a government loan to pay for construction. Senior Citizens Housing of Ann Arbor also became the governing body for Lurie Terrace.
The Lurie Terrace records include documentation from Senior Citizens Housing of Ann Arbor, the organization responsible for the building, funding, and administration of the apartment building. Most important of these records are minute books of the organization's board of directors. The Office Topical Files are materials of Shata Ling who was instrumental in the building and operation and management of Lurie Terrace. These files include history and background information, biographical information about Ling, and documentation of Lurie Terrace's various anniversary celebrations. The Newsletters provide a complete perspective on the life and activities of the residents of the building. Within the scrapbooks, most them compiled by individual residents, the researcher will find photographs of group activities, holiday events, and individual informal photos of residents.
Subjects:
Ann Arbor (Mich.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Apartment houses--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Ling, Shata Lurie.; Lurie Terrace.; Older people--Housing--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Older people--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Senior Citizens Housing of Ann Arbor.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Ann Arbor (Mich.); Aged persons--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Aged persons--Structures--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Apartment houses--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Lurie Terrace.
Contributors:
Ling, Shata Lurie.
Genre Terms:
Albums.; CD-ROMs.; Photographs.
- Senior Citizens Housing of Ann Arbor
  - Board of Directors minute books 1963-1984, 7 volumes; 4 folders (Box 1)
  - Board of Directors minute books 1984-2002, 7 volumes (Box 2)
  - Financial statements and audits (Section 202 Funds, Terrace Funds, etc.) circa 1964-2000 (Box 3)
  - Financial statements and audits (Section 202 Funds, Terrace Funds, etc.) circa 1964-2000 (Box 4)
    (continued)
- Office Topical Files
  - Advertisement for bids 1963 (Box 5)
  - Anniversary materials
    - 15th 1979 (Box 5)
    - 20th 1984, 3 folders (Box 5)
    - 25th 1989 (Box 5)
  - Annual Report 1965 (Box 5)
  - Board miscellaneous, 2 folders (Box 5)
  - Budget (operating expenses) 1965-1968, 2 folders (Box 5)
  - Building: groundbreaking and dedication telegrams and letters 1962, 1964 (Box 5)
  - Bylaws (Box 5)
  - Correspondence 1961-1967, 1969, 8 folders (Box 5)
  - Dining Room / Food Services, 4 folders (Box 5)
  - History / Background Information, 3 folders (Box 5)
  - Ling (Shata) memorial and biographical material, 2 folders (Box 5)
  - Litigation and legal, 3 folders (Box 6)
  - Memorial committee (Box 6)
  - Residents Councils, 3 folders (Box 6)
  - Senior Citizens Guild, 2 folders (Box 6)
  - Senior Citizens Housing of Housing (health maintenance program) (Box 6)
  - Time Capsule (Box 6)
  - Writings and memories (Box 6)
- Residents Newsletter
  - Lurie Terrace News, From the Terrace, 1969-2003, 2008, 34 folders (Box 6)
- Photograph albums
  - Pictorial History of Lurie, including photos of the building and individual rooms (Box 7)
  - Ella E. Redies albums
    - "Lurie Terrace Memories," 1960s-1970s, 3 volumes (Box 7)
      (volumes no. 1-3)
    - "Lurie Terrace Memories," 1980s, 3 volumes (Box 8)
      (volumes no. 4-6)
    - "Lurie Terrace Memories," 1980s, 1 volumes (Box 9)
      (volume no. 7)
    - "Lurie Terrace Memories," 1987-1988, 1 volumes (Box 9)
      (no number)
    - Elsie Gunther's 99th Birthday August, 1988, 1 volumes (Box 9)
  - General and special events
    - 1990-1992 (Box 9)
    - 1992-1993 (Box 9)
    - 1992-1993 (photos by Helen Brown) (Box 9)
    - 1994 (Box 10)
    - 1994-1996 (Box 10)
  - Hazel Messner and Stefanie Beck album 1987 (Box 10)
  - "Past Social Scenes" Esther Abate (Box 10)
  - Miscellaneous 1985-1989 (Box 10)
  - Photographs / Newsletters, 6 optical disks CD-ROMs (Box 10)
  - Albums / Scrapbooks 1961-1980s (Volume 1)
  - Albums / Scrapbooks 1961-1980s (Volume 2)
  - Albums / Scrapbooks 1961-1980s (Volume 3)
  - Lurie Terrace 1st Christmas 1964 (Volume 4)
  - Portrait album (Volume 5)
    (arranged alphabetically)
    (no. 5)